# PERSONAL DETAILS

**Mobile** : 0273833901

E-mail : duffy.stewart@gmail.com

Linkedin : <a href="http://nz.linkedin.com/in/stewartduffy">http://nz.linkedin.com/in/stewartduffy</a>

# **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

2008 Bachelor of Arts (University of Waikato – New Zealand)

Majoring in Marketing and Screen and Media Studies

2010 Diploma of Digital Media (Media Design School, New Zealand)

Industry Panel Award - Highly Commended for Technical Achievement.

## **PROFILE**

An **award winning Front-End and WordPress Developer** with over five years commercial experience with a variety of clients in multiple industry sectors, including Education, Retail, Telecommunications, Print Media, Government and Advertising. Core skills include HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress theme development.

Equally as happy getting stuck into a solo project as thrashing out ideas in a cross-discipline team to develop a solution. Enjoys a challenge and strives for continual improvement to develop in better, quicker, more efficient ways which has enabled successful training and mentoring of colleagues.

Excellent communication skills proven through effectively working with people from both technical and non-technical backgrounds. Motivated by bringing designs to life.

Available from the 9<sup>th</sup> of March for starts in Auckland.

# **TECHNICAL SKILL SUMMARY:**

Job Title: Front-End / JavaScript Developer

**Languages/Technologies:** HTML5, HTML, XHTML, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP,

XML, JSON, ActionScript 3.

Frameworks/Libraries: Knockout.js, AngularJS, RequireJS, Backbone.js, Marionette,

Sammy.JS, Google Maps API, CKEditor, Sass, Compass, LESS, Grunt, Twitter Bootstrap, Modernizr, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, PhoneGap, Sencha Touch, WordPress, Highcharts.

**Databases:** MySQL.

Software: Sublime Text, SVN, GIT, Codebase and DeployHQ, Jenkins

CI, Jira, Confluence, Adobe Fireworks, Photoshop, Illustrator,

Flash, Soundbooth.

**Project experience:** SaaS, UI development, Facebook applications, web

applications, mobile web applications, responsive design, WordPress theme and plug-in development, API integration,

YouTube brand channel, Touchscreen Kiosks.

**Operating systems:** Windows XP, Vista, 2007, Mac OS X.

# REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

### Jul 2012 - Present

### **ELGIN, United Kingdon**

ELGIN's primary product is roadworks.org, a web based service that delivers real-time access to official roadworks information from over 140 public bodies. The services are also embeddable into  $3^{rd}$  party web sites, with an API that exposes advanced features and options.

# JavaScript / Front-End Developer.

This was initally a 3 month contract, which was renewed twice, then turned into a permanent position. Contracted as a Front End developer to work on the existing roadworks.org web application, and develop the traffic management application. Primarily working in a team four on this project, but often working as part of a larger team to focus on the wider business direction. It is standard practice at Elgin to be involved in pair programming and code reviews to ensure the best product is delivered. This role is highly JavaScript orientated with a focus on good quality and maintainable code.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Scoping of project deliverables and refinement of functional, design and system architecture specifications.
- Research and development with emerging web technologies / frameworks and implement suitable solutions to roadworks.org.
- Cross browser and platform testing of software deliverables.
- Front-End development in both a team and solo environment.
- Working closely with the Project Manager and Senior Developers to help deliver the best solutions to fulfil both technical and business specifications.
- Participate in regular Scrum and Sprint Planning meetings to discuss development progress, plan next steps and uncover any blocks in progress.
- Track development done in Codebase & Jira against assigned tickets, and commit projects using either GIT or SVN.

Some of the projects I worked on while at Elgin are:

#### 1. Roadworks Portal

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pr9UkkmObQA http://roadworks.org/

Roadworks.org is a publishing platform used by utility companies and local authorities throughout the United Kingdom. The data published on this system mainly consists of roadworks, traffic incidents and accidents, events and non-streetworks activities and other specialised data layers such as HGV and winter gritting routes. The platform also provides an email alerting system & a journey planner.

This project is built with JavaScript and utilizes BackboneJS and RequireJS to give structure to the application using the AMD format. The application is an embeddable service which relies on a script loader that is called using the API, the loader will then fetch any dependencies and load them into the page. All the HTML elements are created with JavaScript, we use the underscore.js library as a JavaScript templating engine, this means we can use real HTML files, which are then fetched using RequireJS and rendered to the page. The application is optimized using a Node.Js & Grunt build process that runs as part of a Jenkins continuous integration system.

### 2. Traffic Management App:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n81OBBh7F8A

The Traffic Management app is built on top of the roadworks.org platform, and allows subscribing Local Authorities to create Traffic Management Plans. This allows operational staff to plot road closures & associated diversion routes. The UI is built using the Google Maps API, so plotting traffic management is a drag & drop process. This data can then be published to the roadworks.org platform, and be used to generate PDF documents (based on templates the app allows users to set up), which are then used as legal documentation to action the Temporary Traffic Regulation Order.

This project uses the roadwork.org API for many functions and shares a similar development stack. It is built with HTML5, JavaScript using RequireJS to handle AMD patterns & KnockoutJS to handle application view & logic. It is a single-page application, so it uses Sammy.js to handle routing. Twitter bootstrap is used to aid with UI components, and for CSS we use Sass with Compass as a preprocessor. CKEditor is used as a WYSIWYG editor for the PDF document generation.

# **Technical snapshot:**

SaaS, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Knockout.js, RequireJS, Backbone.js, Marionette, Sammy.JS, Google Maps API, CKEditor, JSON, AJAX, HTML5, XHTML, SASS, Compass, CSS, CSS3, Grunt, Twitter Bootstrap, Photoshop CS5, GIT, Codebase, Jira, JSLint, Modernizr, Responsive Design.

#### Mar 2012 – Jun 2012

#### **Isobar Mobile, United Kingdon**

Isobar Mobile are a full-service mobile agency with a focus on cross platform development deliver solutions for Smart phones, Feature phones, Tablets and Web. Isobar's clients include Diageo, Kellogg's, Vodafone, DHL and The Royal Navy.

# Front-End Web Developer.

Contracted as a Front-End Web Developer to work on client project, as part of a team of 25. I worked on a number of projects primarily targeting mobile devices which involved a mixture of Front-End, WordPress and API integration.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Front-End development in both a team and solo environment.
- Working closely with the Project Manager, Strategy and UX Designer to help deliver solutions based on the technologies available.
- Participate in daily Scrum meetings to discuss development progress, plan next steps and uncover any blocks in progress.
- Work together with Senior PHP developer to help scope and plan out tasks required for the Front-End development of the Pimm's Facebook application.
- Act as technical Front-End lead to brief and assist the other Front-End developers on client projects.
- To track development done in Codebase against assigned tickets, and commit projects using either GIT of SVN.

Some of the projects I worked on while at Isobar Mobile are:

### 1. It's Pimm's O'Clock Facebook / Mobile Application:

This was a large project for Diageo which included native applications for both iPhone and Android, as well as an HTML5 Facebook application. The application allows the user to create a Pimm's branded event at participating venues, invite friends and earn rewards that can be used to buy Pimm's party merchandise or redeem discounts on drinks. My role in this project was to work with lead PHP developer to scope and plan out tasks required for Front-End development of the Facebook app. Once the project was scoped, it was my responsibility to work with the other Front-End developers to build the page templates. I was also involved in the development of the Smartphone applications. This included building the web-views that were used throughout the application and developing a splash page that utilised a device detection library that would redirect the user to the app store, marketplace or website accordingly.

# 2. Kellogg's Mobile Strategy Planning Tool:

I was the sole developer on this project, which was an interactive tool to be used internally at Kellogg's. The purpose of this app is to help educate brand managers on the different mobile strategies available, and explain how to use them effectively. WordPress was used as the CMS, but I developed this as *'Single Page'* web application that utilised HTML5 pushState, AJAX and used LESS as a CSS precompiler. It was

important that this site worked cross browser and on iPad. Using combination of CSS3 media queries to detect screen resolution and Modernizr as feature detection, I was able to ensure that the best user experience was delivered based on the devices capabilities.

# **Technical snapshot:**

HTML5, XHTML, CSS, CSS3, LESS, JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, XML, Highcharts JS, Geckoboard, Twitter Bootstrap, Photoshop CS5, GIT, SVN, Codebase, JSHint, Facebook applications, Vimeo API, YouTube API, WURFL, Modernizr, Responsive Design.

## Sept 2011 - Jan 2012

### Born Digital, New Zealand

Born Digital design and develop websites, SaaS applications, touch screens, mobile apps, and content management solutions. Born Digital have developed work for some of Australasia's biggest brands, including Vodafone, Microsoft, Air New Zealand and Hyundai.

### Front-End Web Developer.

Employed as Technical Front-End Web Developer as part of a team of 9, to maintain existing sites as well as develop new projects for clients. I was also responsible for researching new techniques, mainly HTML5 alternatives to flash as most projects needed to work on both desktop and mobile devices.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Utilise responsive design techniques to develop sites for clients that span across multiple platforms; Mobile, tablet and desktop.
- Act as technical Front-End lead and assist junior Front-End developer with problems.
- Research new techniques, libraries and technologies applicable to upcoming projects, and educate other team members.
- Work and communicate with web designer to ensure that the solution offered to client best meets brief and technical specification with in platform limits.
- Communicate with Back-End developers, to ensure Front-End integrates smoothly with CMS and Database design.

Some of the projects I worked on while at Born Digital are:

# 1. ASB Bank "Experience ASB" social media campaign:

This project, was part of a larger social strategy that ASB Bank were undertaking, this involved a custom YouTube brand channel, Facebook applications, Twitter and an interactive HTML5 web page. It was my sole responsibility to develop a YouTube gadget, which would be used in a custom YouTube Brand Channel. The Gadget was developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM Scripting, and utilised the YouTube API to pull videos into the gadget. The project also involved the development of a Facebook application; this was built using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and PHP. This also utilised YouTube API integration. All the designs were supplied by the client in fireworks format; it was my responsibility to ensure that end product matched the designs precisely.

### 2. iSurf wireless hotspot signup page:

iSurf provides prepaid wireless broadband around Waiheke Island and Auckland City. The brief for this project was to develop a cross device signup and registration page for the wireless hotspot service. To achieve this, I developed a responsive website which was built using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP and utilised media queries to style the page to suit the screen resolution. This was tested cross platform and device and worked on Android, iPhone and iPad as well as desktop.

### **Achievements:**

• Successfully implemented new solutions for mobile application development through research and evaluation, pitching options to team members and then training staff in the new the technology to ensure the companies ongoing competitive edge.

• Effectively implementing and documenting new front-end optimisation procedures to reduce page load time and rank better on Google searches. Educating staff of these to ensure these practices are continued.

### **Technical snapshot:**

HTML5, XHTML, CSS, CSS3, Sass, Compass, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, ActionScript 3, ActionScript 2, XML, jQuery mobile, Sencha Touch, WordPress, Flash CS5, Photoshop CS5, Fireworks CS5, Phone Gap, SVN, YouTube Gadgets, Facebook applications, Vimeo API integration.

#### Nov 2010 - Sept 2011

#### &some, New Zealand

&some create and build physical computing interfaces, applications (web & mobile), digital strategies, interactive installations, data driven insights, projection mapping installations, live visuals. Some of &somes' clients include IBM, Hewlett Packard, NZ Post and Heineken.

## Web Developer.

Employed to develop new web sites and applications, maintain existing client's sites. This position involved a mixture of Front-End development and PHP / WordPress development.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Working as a Web Developer to support, maintain and update clients' websites.
- Dealing with clients to provide training and on-going support for CMS based products.
- Communicate with Back-End developers, to ensure Front-End integrates smoothly with CMS and Database design.
- Develop custom WordPress themes from scratch to meet project brief.
- Develop custom WordPress plug-ins to extend functionality of clients' customised WordPress theme.
- Meeting with clients, to help scope the proposed projects.

Some of the projects I worked on while at &some are:

# 1. Hydra WordPress Framework.

### http://www.stevensonconcrete.co.nz

The brief for this project was to develop a highly customised WordPress theme and a series of plug-ins to accompany the theme. This theme had to be modular, abstracted and easy to skin for junior developers that have no knowledge of PHP. It also had to be highly customisable for the client yet easy to use for people new to the CMS. I achieved this by developing from scratch a 'parent' WordPress theme that handled the functionality and base styles, and then there was a 'child' theme that enabled us to rapidly skin the theme for different clients. This was developed on the WordPress framework with XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP. The theme included custom widgets, shortcodes, font replacement, custom post types, custom fields and custom admin panels. As part of this framework I developed plug-ins to handle the following, editable contact form, google maps API, drag and drop post reordering.

### **Achievements:**

- Successfully developed and documented a modular, re-usable WordPress framework was cost efficient for the client and profitable for the company.
- After the magazine digital re-launch, analytics proved that there was an increase of traffic to the site of over 200% throughout the month of re-launch.

### **Technical snapshot:**

HTML5, XHTML, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, XML, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, jQuery mobile, WordPress, WordPress Theme Development, WordPress Plug-in Development, Django, Photoshop CS5, Fireworks CS5, SVN.